

João Vitor de Souza

linkedin.com/in/souzavitor https://vitordesouza.github.io/

contatovitorsouza@gmail.com

934347000

Summary

I'm a Brazilian software developer with nine years of experience in programming and a passion for creating valuable virtual experiences. I focus on Javascript and Typescript applications, and I've been living and working in Portugal since 2018.

Skills

Next.js • React.js • Vue.js • TypeScript • JavaScript • SQL • GraphQL • REST APIs • Tailwind CSS

Experience

Javascript Developer

INFORM GmbH - Optimization Software

Jan 2023 - Jan 2024 (1 year 1 month)

I helped develop and optimise web frontends of a workforce management set of solutions that facilitates the operation of global companies such as airports, airlines, retailer chains, etc.

In a self-organised team I shared full ownership on the (continuous) delivery of the software, including design, code, testing, support and operation of the product;

I worked closely with UX/UI team and stakeholders to ensure an appealing user experience.

Played important role on the migration of an older solution to newer and more secure technologies using Typescript and Next.js.

cci Frontend Developer

CGI

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022 (4 months)

I contributed to migrating an application from JSP to React.js, maintaining and improving a system comprised of Node web services. I used Typescript, React.js and Node.

Throughout the process, I performed code-reviews, created automated tests and worked on support by fixing bugs and implementing custom solutions for clients.

Frontend Developer

Valtech

Jul 2021 - Jul 2022 (1 year 1 month)

I joined a starting project to build a high-performance B2C web app for a global audit, tax and advisory firm that streamlined, simplified and digitalised the communication with their clients and the safe and fast exchange and signage of sensitive legal and private documents.

I worked closely with UI/UX to plan and design. Joined the back-end team in designing the API contracts and played key role in helping team managers and stakeholders in estimating, prioritising and creating a timeline for the project.

Using Vue.js, JavaScript and Typescript. I wrote quality code, conducted testing, reviewed code. I owned features and co-led feature teams. I produced research and made technology choices.

B Frontend Web Developer

Brief Creatives

Nov 2019 - Mar 2021 (1 year 5 months)

I was responsible for crafting and maintaining websites and mobile applications for a wide range of clients, including renowned brands such as Bayer, and Bepanthen.

I leveraged modern and flexible tech stacks, including React.js, Vue.js, Ionic, WordPress, and Shopify to make these solutions flexible, extendable and long-lasting.

Full Stack Web Developer

EYESO

Jan 2019 - Aug 2019 (8 months)

At EYESO, I worked as a Full Stack to develop and launch to beta version, a marketplace/social-network web application that empowers artists selling their photography and digital art, and powers brands looking to use that art commercially.

Using Vue.js, Symfony, Agile methodologies, SOLID principles, modular, clean and tested code we created a beautiful and powerful platform for creative artists to showcase their art to their public, to peers and brands.

COPYTRACK

Full Stack Web Developer

COPYTRACK GmbH

Apr 2018 - Dec 2018 (9 months)

I worked as a full stack developer to improve and expand a data- driven SAAS web application used by hundreds of thousand users worldwide to find stolen images and enforce copyrights.

This involved planning, designing and refining, developing and fixing bugs, to create and roll out new features like a totally new onboarding flow, a new profile area and dashboard, among others.

Developing modular, clean and testable code, I used technologies such as ElasticSearch, Javascript,

MySQL, PHP and Symfony then worked on the continuous deployment of these solutions on AWS.

W Full Stack Web Developer

Ótima Ideia

Apr 2016 - Dec 2017 (1 year 9 months)

At this full-service marketing and web agency in São Paulo, I developed, improved and maintained a wide range of products such as websites, e-commerce applications, portals, blogs and back-office tools for big clients in the national Brazilian market.

I collaborated and received instruction from very skilled senior developers on many stacks and technologies. So I learned and worked with Symfony, Laravel, Magento, Twig and other templating languages, Vue.js and React.js were a pleasure to discover.

E-commerce Web Developer

Allstore Shop

Apr 2015 - Jul 2016 (1 year 4 months)

For AllStore I crafted an innovative e-commerce platform and a dynamic blog. Using my expertise in PHP, MySQL, Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, and CSS3, I designed and implemented a custom WooCommerce powered Wordpress theme, along with necessary plugins and API integrations for seamless functionality.

Freelance Web Developer

Catorze Digital

Jan 2013 - Apr 2015 (2 years 4 months)

After my technical education I identified an audience of local businesses and companies that were untapped or sometimes underserved but wanted/needed software services.

So I worked as a freelancer, developing websites, intranet tools, web integration, API's and plugins. Using Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, JS, Jquery, HTML5 and CSS3.

It helped me become a quick learner and solution driven professional.

Education

Escola Técnica Estadual de Praia Grande - Centro Paula Souza

Technical, Information Technology 2010 - 2012

Universidade Católica de Santos

Bacharelado, Relações Internacionais 2014 - 2018